# Nikhil kumar K

#### CONTACT

nikhilk00821@gmail.com 9600057219

#### PERSONAL SUMMARY

Been working at Cognizant for the past two years as a front-end developer. Worked on three web applications and gained good knowledge on web development. Well versed with front-end frameworks - Angular and React. An excellent problem solver.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Cognizant Technology Solutions India Pvt. Ltd..

28th Jun 2016 — Present

Programmer Analyst

- Worked on "FDA", a web application of client Novartis, from November, 2017 to April, 2018. Technology stack was ReactJS, Redux, NodeJS, ExpressJS and SQL Server. Part of Front-end development team. Involved in Back-end development as well.
- Worked on "DIANE", a web application of client Societe Generale, from July, 2017 to November, 2017. Technology stack was Angular 5 and Spring. Part of Front-end development team.
- Worked on "BIA Tool", a web application of client Societe Generale, from December, 2016 to June, 2017. Technology stack was AngularJS 1.6 and Spring. Part of Front-end development team.
- Worked on "Ekart", awebapplication, as part of MFRP at Cognizant. Technology stack was AngularJS, NodeJS, ExpressJS and MongoDB (MEAN Stack). It got selected as the best project of the batch.

## **EDUCATION**

B. Tech. in CSE Aug 2012 — May 2016

SRM University, Kattankulathur

Secured 8.2 CGPA out of 10.

12th Standard Jun 2011 — Mar 2012

Narayana Junior College, Hyderabad

Secured 91.1% of marks in state board's exams (11th and 12th combined).

10th Standard Jun 2009 — Apr 2010

Bhashyam High School, Hyderabad

Secured 93.2% of marks in state board's exams.

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- **Frameworks:** Angular 5, AngularJS, ReactJS and Redux.
- **Programming Languages:** JavaScript, ES 6, OOJS and TypeScript.
- **Web Design:** HTML 5, CSS 3, Responsive Web Design and Bootstrap 3.
- CSS Pre-processors: LESS and SASS.
- **Backend Frameworks:** NodeJS and ExpressJS.
- **Databases:** MongoDB and SQL Server.

Nikhil kumar K

- Unit Testing: Jasmine, Karma and Protractor.
- **Tools:** Git, Jira and Jenkins.
- C, C++ and SQL.

#### **ACCOLADES**

- Awarded with monthly AVM Sparkle Award June'17 for contributions towards BIA Tool application.
- Been appreciated by leads and project managers for keeping up with the deadlines.
- Received many appreciation emails from the client.

## PERSONALITY TRAITS

- Have sound communication skills.
- Able to work under pressure.
- Quick at learning new technologies.

## CO CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

- Completed B. Tech. final year project titled, "Delay-optimized File Retrieval using LT-based cloud storage".
- Participated in "Big Data Analytics" workshop organized by C-DAC at SRM University during Aaruush'14 and have got trained on Hadoop Eco System Tools.
- Attended "Ethical Hacking Expert (Integrated Level 1.0 & 2.0)", a two-day workshop conducted by TechDefence at SRM University during Aaruush'14.
- Participated in "Parallel Programming Basics", a one-day workshop conducted by Calligo Technologies and have gained knowledge in High Performance Computing (HPC).
- Underwent an Inplant Training on "C++ and Java" from Cognizance Professional Solutions LLP, Chennai.

## EXTRA CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

- Participated in various social activities conducted by Outreach of Cognizant.
- Volunteered for several roadshows and fests that have been conducted in Cognizant.
- Member of NSS club during B.Tech.

## PERSONAL DETAILS

- Date of Birth: 26-12-1993
- Gender: Male
- Passport Status: Active

I hereby declare that the above information furnished by me is true to the best of my knowledge.

Hyderabad Nikhil kumar K 6th July, 2018

Nikhil kumar K